In this video, we will learn about the knowledge of the arrangement point and arrangement board.
First of all, when we import a virtual model, if it is an OBJ file, it will automatically generate an arrangement board when it is imported.
Whether it is imported from the file folder or imported from the upper left corner, it is the same way.
Here, confirm the type of download and the type of object, and confirm the unit at the bottom.
It will pop up a pop-up window to remind you that you cannot arrange the arrangement point on the virtual model.
Generally speaking, there are several possibilities for this pop-up window to pop up.
The first is that your posture makes the system unable to identify a more accurate A or T pose.
Or your model may be a virtual model with a more special shape.
Or your proportion unit has some problems.
The proportion unit is relatively easy to solve.
Just import the unit and pay attention to it.
Here I import a virtual model with a posture that is the standard A pose.
After this model is imported, we press Shift F to see if there is an arrangement point.
Or select the display arrangement point in the vertical guide list.
You can see that there will be an automatic arrangement point generated.
This is because it is a virtual model.
This is because our current action is an A pose that is easier to identify.
So when you import a virtual model, it is best not to make your arm too high.
Click on the board and then click on the arrangement point to arrange the board around the virtual model.
If we want to change the arrangement board or arrangement point, or if we want to create an arrangement board or arrangement point,
we can go to the main menu and find the virtual model editor.
There is a virtual model editor at the bottom of the virtual model main menu.
After opening it, we find the arrangement point.
As we find the arrangement, we can see that the green arrangement board and the blue arrangement point will be displayed in the 3D space.
When we arrange a board on the arrangement point, it will be placed along the shape of the green arrangement board.
Whether we click on the name at the bottom of the arrangement board or the name at the bottom of the arrangement point,
the corresponding objects will be displayed in yellow.
Here we will find that the name will have a lowercase A or a lowercase L at the back.
This means that they are symmetrical.
If I create a board and press Ctrl D, I can create a symmetrical board.
In this way, whether they are editing or creating a sewing line, they are linked.
If I arrange one of the boards on the arrangement point,
the other board will also be automatically arranged on the symmetrical arrangement point.
So when we edit or create an arrangement board or arrangement point,
we can apply such rules to it.
Back to the virtual model editor,
in order to quickly use these arrangement boards and arrangement points,
we can choose to save arrangement boards and arrangement points.
Please note that in general, arrangement points and arrangement boards will have a corresponding principle.
So if you save the arrangement board, you must also remember to save the arrangement points.
In this way, we can use these arrangement boards and arrangement points in another position or another virtual model.
Next, let's take a look at how to edit or create these arrangement boards and arrangement points.
First, let's learn how to create an arrangement board.
Press the plus button on the arrangement board to create an arrangement board.
After creating an arrangement board,
click and drag this arrangement board to move it.
When we select an arrangement board,
its corresponding properties will appear at the bottom of the arrangement.
Here we can modify the length of the entire arrangement board,
as well as its height of x and height of y.
The height of x and y are all modified by the coordinate system of the arrangement board itself.
The height of x and y are different from each other.
Click the arrangement board again to call for an positioning ball.
If using a positioning ball, we can rotate the arrangement board to the correct angle.
In addition, we can switch the arrangement type of arrangement in the arrangement property.
Here we can make a cylinder-type arrangement.
Cuboid is a rectangular shape.
If you choose Cuboid,
when the board is arranged outside the rectangular shape,
it will automatically arrange it into a foldable shape.
Under normal circumstances, we choose Cylinder.
After creating a layout,
we need to create a layout under the layout,
the layout that needs to be placed on this layout board.
First, click Add to create a layout.
After creating a layout,
we find the PAN that we created before.
This is the newly created layout board.
The layout point is placed on this layout board.
But you need to pay attention,
if we adjust or modify this name later,
you may need to manually arrange the board
in the layout point again.
Because our board has changed its name just now,
so here we also need to change the name of the layout point.
It is convenient for us to find it later.
Also, we need to rearrange it on the layout board just now.
If we rotate the rectangle in 3D,
you will see that the layout point has been placed on the layout board.
After placing it on the layout board,
we can adjust the location of the layout point
through X and Y.
X is the level position,
and Y is the position of the vertical axis.
When the layout point is placed on the layout board,
this point will lean outward.
Finally, the direction of the package.
If the direction of the package is down,
then this board will rotate from the outside to the inside
according to the direction of the vertical axis.
If the direction of the package is up,
then the direction of the vertical axis
will rotate from the outside to the inside.
Next, let's learn how to create a symmetrical layout board.
First, you still need to build a layout board,
and set it to the same value as the previous layout board.
And the name of the layout board,
we need to set it to the name corresponding to the previous layout board.
But here we need to add the lower line,
the capital R,
and the original one,
we need to add the lower line,
the capital L.
If the layout board needs to be set to be symmetrical,
it must be named according to this naming rule.
Next, we set the value of this new layout board
to be the same as the previous one.
Then we manually arrange it with the positioning ball tool.
In the process of adjustment,
if your positioning ball is different from my positioning ball,
you can right-click the positioning ball in the 3D space,
and select the world coordinate.
If the default screen coordinate,
it will be fixed according to the lens of the screen.
In order to make it more convenient to use,
you can switch the positioning ball to the world coordinate.
After the layout board is created,
we can start to create the arrangement points.
Here the adjustment method is the same as the layout board.
It is also to create a new arrangement point,
and then create it in accordance with the name of the previous arrangement point.
After creating,
arrange them separately on the corresponding layout board.
After the arrangement is completed,
we need to save the layout board and the arrangement points for the second time,
and then import them to ensure that their symmetry is in use.
After opening it for the second time,
let's test it.
After importing,
we can click on one of the arrangement points here,
and we can see that another arrangement point will automatically display light blue.
This means that they are now in a symmetrical state.
Now when I put this board on the symmetrical layout board,
another board will also automatically be placed on the symmetrical layout board.
In addition, let's take a look at this kind of non-automatically generated layout board.
Whether it is an FBX file or an OBJ file,
we can use the layout board under another model that has been saved before,
on this model.
Here we open it for the second time,
we can see the arrangement board and the arrangement points that have been saved before.
After opening it,
we can manually place these arrangement boards in the right place.
It is still the same,
you can use the positioning ball to rotate and move these symmetrical arrangement boards.
After we place these arrangement boards,
considering that this model may be used for the second time,
we can save this virtual model again.
After we open it for the second time,
it will also have arrangement points and arrangement boards.
Here we open the virtual model that we just saved,
and then we press Shift F,
we can see that there are arrangement points and arrangement boards around this virtual model.
This means that if we enter the model we love,
it has no arrangement points and we have no other positions,
then you can use the virtual model that comes with the software.
They themselves have a set of arrangement points and arrangement boards.
You can modify this set of arrangement points and arrangement boards to match your virtual model.
Of course,
arrangement points and arrangement boards are not necessarily created for each model.
It's just that with arrangement points and arrangement boards,
it may be more convenient for us to make clothes.
When we choose an arrangement board,
there will be a joint name 0 and a joint name 1 at the bottom.
By setting these two properties to the arrangement board,
we can lock the arrangement board between these two joints.
First, we need to make sure that this model has a skeleton.
After confirming,
close and display the skeleton.
This way,
we can continue to adjust the arrangement board.
When choosing an arrangement board,
we need to fill in its joint name.
First of all,
the first joint name here,
I chose the leg,
and then the second one,
I chose the foot.
In this way,
this arrangement board will lock with my whole leg.
If I change the position of one of the end points,
the position of this arrangement board will also be changed.
In order to bind it correctly,
we change the joint name 1 to the joint point of the foot.
Now,
let's change the position of its leg.
Press Shift X to open and edit the skeleton.
Here we rotate its leg.
You can see that only the two arrangement boards of the virtual model joint points
that have just been tied to the virtual model joint points
have changed according to the position of the model.
Now we press Ctrl Z to return to the position of the sphincter just now.
You can also see that these two arrangement points will change with each other.
So I recommend that you can use these arrangement boards
and its skeleton to lock the virtual model joint points.
See you in the next video, bye bye.